Finding Aid to the Gloria Steinem papers SSC.MS.00237
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES V. ORGANIZATIONS, 1970-96
  Scholars have already noted that the magazine's business end was by and large more traditional than its editorial practice, an insight documented in the records associated with Advertising, Circulation and distribution, and Financial and legal matters. Materials here document the magazine's heroic effort to remain afloat, including the securing of advertisers willing to forego complementary copy, and donors anxious to support the magazine and/or the foundation. Marketing analyses rate Ms. readers in comparison to other women's magazines.
  Philanthropy has always been closely associated with the Ms. project. Not long after the magazine was launched, the Ms. Foundation for Women was established to further the feminist cause. Steinem has described the Ms. Foundation for Women as the "grant-giving mother with two daughters who do her outreach work": the Free to Be Foundation, and the Ms. Foundation for Education and Communication. The Free to Be Foundation was formed as a supporting organization of the Ms. Foundation for Women "to develop and disseminate educational materials which challenge stereotypes, stress individuality, and eliminate barriers of prejudice and discrimination." Its first series, "Free to be... You and Me," was developed by board members Marlo Thomas and Letty Cottin Pogrebin. A second series, "Free to Be... A Family," explores the many varieties of family life. While the Ms. Foundation for Women continues to thrive, the Ms. Foundation for Education and Communication, as of 1998, was dismantled.
  The National Women's Political Caucus (NWPC) was founded in July 1971 in a conference of about three hundred women leaders that Newsweek magazine called "rowdy" but which, it also noted, produced a "plausible definition and a strategy for a women's political movement where none had existed before." The Caucus was launched quickly in the public mind as an important new political development thanks to extensive media reporting of its founding and subsequent activities. The early attention paid to the NWPC probably resulted from the status and celebrity of many of its founders, as well as its potential to influence the 1972 Presidential nominations and elections. After the elections concluded, the NWPC rapidly became the media's main source of information and comment about women in politics. (The NWPC Records are located at the Schlesinger Library, Harvard College).
  Records of the NWPC in Steinem's papers date largely from the early to mid 1970s and include agendas, minutes, and memoranda from committees and subcommittees, as well as material pertaining to in-house business, such as political conventions and elections of NWPC officers. Of particular interest in the latter regard is a memoranda from Bella Abzug detailing what she perceived to be election fraud surrounding her 1989 defeat for the Caucus chair. For Steinem's speech nominating Irene Natividad as chair of the National Women's Political Caucus, see SERIES III. SPEECHES AND APPEARANCES--speech texts, 1985; for her address before the NWPC convention in San Antonio, Texas, 9 July 1983, see SERIES IX. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIAL-audiotapes.
  Voters for Choice was founded in 1979 to combat the emerging right wing in the elections of 1980. A founding member, Steinem also sat on the Board of Directors. In 1984, Voters for Choice merged with the Friends of Family Planning. Materials include memoranda, minutes and agendas from the Board of Directors, 1979 - 86; lists of donors; campaign strategy handbooks; and research materials, including clippings, articles and reports on abortion rights and voting behavior, as well as polling data from Lou Harris and Gallup. The latter includes information regarding women's attitudes toward U.S. involvement in Vietnam.
  In 1971, Steinem, along with Brenda Feigen and Catherine Samuels, co-founded the Women's Action Alliance (whose records are also held by the Sophia Smith Collection). Conceived of as an advisory service that could provide back-up support for existing women's groups, the WAA worked to coordinate resources for organizations and individuals involved in the women's movement, with a particular emphasis on the grass-roots level. The organization's original mission was "to stimulate and aid women at the local level to organize... specific action projects [e.g. child care, job training and placement, legislative action, political lobbying, etc.] aimed at eliminating concrete manifestations of economic and social discrimination." Steinem served as chair of the WAA's Board of Directors from 1971 to 1978, and through the 1980s assisted with fundraising projects to benefit the Alliance.
  Records of the Women's Action Alliance in Gloria Steinem's papers include agendas; budgets and financial reports; minutes; memoranda; and reports pertaining to the operations of the WAA and similar material pertaining to the many programs the WAA developed between 1971 and 1986. Though the WAA persisted until 1997, Steinem's papers document only the WAA's first fifteen years. For additional information, researchers should consult the records of the WAA itself, also housed in the Sophia Smith Collection. Especially useful information regarding the inner workings of the organization is contained in a folder related to "Personnel." Two essays filed under "Institutional histories" are also interesting in this regard.
  Women USA, launched in April 1979, aimed to motivate women on several levels. Responding to a "rising mood of militancy" among American women, the founders of Women USA - Bella Abzug, Yvonne Burke, Patsy T. Mink, Maggie Kuhn, Brownie Ledbetter, and Gloria Steinem -- sought to harness that energy by, for example, organizing lobbying efforts on social and economic issues and orchestrating mass letter-writing campaigns. The group also established a toll-free telephone number by which to distribute information. The comparatively small number of documents here include the group's 1979 articles of incorporation, as well as early correspondence, outreach materials, and press releases.
  The Wonder Woman Foundation, funded by Warner Communications, Inc. together with D.C. Comics, Inc., was launched in September 1981, on the 40th anniversary of the appearance of the comic book heroine of the same name. The Foundation was "dedicated to advancing the principles of equality for women in American society." Unlike most foundations, which fund only projects and groups, the Wonder Woman Foundation provided financial support for individual women. The Foundation's founding executive director was Koryne Horbal. Though Steinem was among the organization's founders and early supporters, she was not a member of the Board of Directors
  Relatively few materials pertaining to the Wonder Woman Foundation are found among Steinem's papers; records of the WWF are also housed at the SSC, though they are at present closed to research. Materials in Steinem's papers include correspondence, clippings, and printed material, largely pertaining to awards ceremonies.
  - International Women's Year, 1975-78
    - General
      - Anti-IWY activity (Box 139, Folder 1)
      - Clippings (Box 139, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence (Box 139, Folder 3)
      - Encounter for Journalists (Box 139, Folder 4)
      - Fletcher School of Law report on laws discriminating against women (Box 139, Folder 5)
      - International Women's Decade: printed material (Box 139, Folder 6)
      - International Women's Year Arts Festival: proposal (Box 139, Folder 7)
    - International Women's Year state meetings: clippings, questionnaire, and materials re: CA, CT, ID, MI, MT, NV, OH, NY, ND, SC and TN (Box 139, Folder 8-20)
    - National Commission on the International Women's Year
      - Agendas, minutes, budgets, memoranda, notes, and committee materials (Box 139, Folder 21-24)
      - Fact sheets, Mulqueeny v. IWY complaint and ruling,and procedural material (Box 140, Folder 1-8)
    - Houston Convention, 1977
      - Briefing book (Box 140, Folder 9)
      - Delegates-at-large (Box 140, Folder 10)
      - Houston Breakthrough: correspondence and issues (Box 140, Folder 11)
      - Local arrangements (Box 140, Folder 12-15)
      - National Plan of Action (includes reports and memoranda) (Box 141, Folder 1-19)
      - Plenary program (Box 141, Folder 20)
      - Reports
        - "The Spirit of Houston: An Official Report to the President, the Congress, and the People of the United States,", March 1978 (Box 141, Folder 21)
        - What Women Want: from the official report to the President, the Congress, and the people of the United States, by Caroline Bird (Simon & Schuster, 1979): correspondence, drafts, proofs, 1977-78 (Box 141, Folder 22-24)
      - Torch relay: fact sheets and schedules (Box 142, Folder 1)
      - Post-conference correspondence (Box 142, Folder 2)
    - Press: newsletters, press releases, updates, 1976-77; undated (Box 142, Folder 3-7)
  - Minnetonka Corporation
    - Affiliation (minutes and by-laws), 1986; undated (Box 142, Folder 8-9)
    - Board of Directors
      - Annual report, briefing books, business plans, correspondence, and financial statements, 1986-88 (Box 142, Folder 10-22)
      - Financial statements, meeting materials, and memoranda, 1987-89 (Box 143, Folder 1-13)
    - Press releases, 1987-88 (Box 143, Folder 14)
    - Reports, 1987 (Box 143, Folder 15-17)
    - Reports, 1980; 1987; undated (Box 144, Folder 1-3)
    - Securities Exchange Commission: annual and quarterly reports, questionnaires, 1987-89 (Box 144, Folder 4-5)
  - Ms. Foundation for Women
    - Annual reports and updates, 1977-85 (Box 144, Folder 6-7)
    - Board of Directors
      - Committees and correspondence, 1977-91; undated (Box 144, Folder 9-10)
      - Meeting materials
        - 1976-95 (Box 145, Folder 1-8)
        - 1996 (Box 146, Folder 1)
      - Gloria Steinem, Marie Wilson correspondence, 1977-91; undated (Box 146, Folder 2-3)
    - Contributions and fundraising (includes Garry Trudeau), 1977-88 (Box 146, Folder 5-8)
    - Correspondence, general, 1976-86 (Box 146, Folder 9)
    - Financial, 1974-89 (Box 146, Folder 10)
    - Grants and proposals, 1976-87 (Box 146, Folder 11-13)
    - History, 1979; undated (Box 146, Folder 14)
    - Notes and miscellaneous, 1982-88; undated (Box 146, Folder 15)
    - Press clippings, 1987-88 (Box 146, Folder 16)
    - Promotional materials, 1978-87; undated (Box 146, Folder 17)
    - Special projects
      - General, 1989; undated (Box 146, Folder 18)
      - 20th anniversary, 1993 (Box 146, Folder 19)
      - The Artist's Circle, 1993 (Box 146, Folder 20)
      - Benefits, 1979-1991; undated (Box 147, Folder 1)
      - Breaking Silence, 1985 (Box 147, Folder 2)
      - Charter membership, 1984 (Box 147, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 147, Folder 4)
      - Ms. dinners, 1981; undated (Box 147, Folder 5)
      - The Pro-Choice Project, 1979-80 (Box 147, Folder 6)
      - Pro-Choice Project on Reproductive Freedom TrainingWorkshop, 11-13 Jan 1981 (Box 147, Folder 7-8)
      - Reproductive rights projects, 1981-86 (Box 147, Folder 9)
      - Studies of the Foundation, 1989; undated (Box 147, Folder 10)
      - Subject files, 1980; undated (Box 147, Folder 11-12)
      - Women's History Research Center, Inc., 1974 (Box 147, Folder 13)
    - Supporting organizations
      - Free to Be Foundation
        - General, 1974-1989; undated (Box 147, Folder 14)
        - Financial statements, 1987 (Box 147, Folder 15)
        - "Free To Be, You and Me": scripts, 1985; undated (Box 147, Folder 16)
        - History, 1978; undated (Box 148, Folder 1)
        - Special events, 1981-82 (Box 148, Folder 2)
      - Ms. Foundation for Education and Communication: General 1989-90, and She's Nobody's Baby, 1983 (Box 148, Folder 3-4)
  - Ms. magazine
    - Advertising
      - Ad Council, 1978-80 (Box 148, Folder 5-7)
      - Ad inserts, 1978; undated (Box 148, Folder 8)
      - Ad rates, 1974-85 (Box 148, Folder 9)
      - Advertisers, 1974-87 (Box 148, Folder 10-17)
      - Analysis and market research, 1974-79 (Box 149, Folder 1-6)
      - Call reports, 1977-80 (Box 149, Folder 7)
      - Classified, 1975-84 (Box 149, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 1972-87 (Box 149, Folder 9-10)
      - Electronics industry, 1978-80; undated (Box 149, Folder 11)
      - Internal correspondence and memoranda, 1976-86; undated (Box 149, Folder 12-13)
      - Notes and miscellaneous, 1972-78; undated (Box 150, Folder 1)
      - Press clippings, 1972-89; undated (Box 150, Folder 2)
      - Promotional materials, 1972-87; undated (Box 150, Folder 3)
      - Sales presentation packets, 1977-78; undated (Box 150, Folder 4)
    - Circulation, 1973-85; undated (Box 150, Folder 5)
    - Distribution, 1976-84; undated (Box 150, Folder 6)
    - Editorial
      - Advisory Board of Scholars, undated (Box 150, Folder 7)
      - Anniversary issues
        - 5th, Jul 1977 (includes interview material with Simone de Beauvoir) (Box 150, Folder 8-9)
        - 15th, 1987 (Box 150, Folder 10)
      - Awards applications: Newswomen's Club of NY, Front Page awards, 1978-79 (Box 150, Folder 11)
      - Campus Times, 1984-93 (Box 151, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence
        - Letters to the Editors and reader responses
          - Cigarette and alcohol ads, 1985 (Box 151, Folder 2)
          - Club ad, 1980 (Box 151, Folder 3)
          - Lesbian coverage, 1975 (Box 151, Folder 4)
          - Letters reports, 1981 (Box 151, Folder 5)
          - NOW exclusion, 1980 (Box 151, Folder 6)
          - Pornography, 1985 (Box 151, Folder 7)
          - Published letters, 1972 (Box 151, Folder 8)
          - Miscellaneous, 1974-80 (Box 151, Folder 9)
        - Steinem, Gloria, 1974-1983 (Box 151, Folder 10-11)
        - Third party
          - Black, Cathleen, 1977 (Box 151, Folder 12)
          - Carbine, Pat, 1972-73; 1978-79 (Box 151, Folder 13)
          - Edgar, Joanne, 1970-1983 (Box 151, Folder 14)
          - Edgar Joanne, 1970-1983 (Box 152, Folder 1-4)
          - Harris, Elizabeth Forsling, 1972 (Box 152, Folder 5)
          - Krauss, Elissa, 1974-75 (Box 152, Folder 6)
          - Levine, Suzanne, 1985 (Box 152, Folder 7)
          - Morgan, Robin, 1978; 1981 (Box 152, Folder 8)
          - Pogrebin, Letty Cottin, 1972; 1986 (Box 152, Folder 9)
          - Robinson, Marianne [Jolly], 1973-1974 (Box 152, Folder 10-11)
          - Other Ms. staff, 1975-91 (Box 153, Folder 1)
          - Miscellaneous, 1972-77 (Box 153, Folder 2)
      - Editorial meetings: minutes, notes, miscellany, 1977-83 (Box 153, Folder 3-5)
      - Editorial statement, undated (Box 153, Folder 6)
      - Index of magazine, 1972-73 (Box 153, Folder 7)
      - Internal correspondence and memoranda, 1973-88; undated (Box 153, Folder 8)
      - Manuscripts and related correspondence
        - Abzug, Bella, undated (Box 153, Folder 9)
        - Anderson, Mary, 1974 (Box 153, Folder 10)
        - Baevsky, Sonia, 1976 (Box 153, Folder 11)
        - Bamburger, Gloria, 1973 (Box 153, Folder 12)
        - Binford, Sally, 1978; undated (Box 153, Folder 13)
        - Blackwell and Ferguson, undated (Box 153, Folder 14)
        - Blair, Bea, 1973 (Box 153, Folder 15)
        - Brennan, Teresa Mary, 1980 (Box 154, Folder 1)
        - Budapest, Zsuzanna, 1973 (Box 154, Folder 2)
        - Cardozo, Yvette, 1973 (Box 154, Folder 3)
        - Cary, Eve, 1974-75 (Box 154, Folder 4)
        - Chambers, Jane, 1972 (Box 154, Folder 5)
        - Chavez, Bernadette, 1974 (Box 154, Folder 6)
        - Clapp, Steve, undated (Box 154, Folder 7)
        - Coburn, Judith (re: Dolores Huerta), 1976 (Box 154, Folder 8)
        - Combs, Joyce, undated (Box 154, Folder 9)
        - Conrad-Wahlberg, Rachel, 1976 (Box 154, Folder 10)
        - Cornblath-Moshe, Nancy, and Carol Burris, 1977 (Box 154, Folder 11)
        - Cunningham, Marilyn, 1983-84 (Box 154, Folder 12)
        - Darling, Anne, 1973 (Box 154, Folder 13)
        - Davis, Elizabeth Gould, 1973 (Box 154, Folder 14)
        - Del Drago, Maria, 1974-75 (Box 154, Folder 15)
        - Dundy, Elaine (re: Liz Smith), 1977 (Box 155, Folder 1)
        - Dworkin, Andrea, 1977-79 (Box 155, Folder 2-5)
        - Dykes, Michael, 1981 (Box 155, Folder 6)
        - Farenthold, Frances Tarlton "Sissy", undated (Box 155, Folder 7)
        - Fritz, Leah, 1977 (Box 155, Folder 8)
        - Geyer, Georgie Anne, 1973-74 (Box 155, Folder 9)
        - Gingold, Judy, 1974-77 (Box 155, Folder 10)
        - Glasser, Ira, 1973 (Box 155, Folder 11)
        - Griffin, Susan, 1984; undated (Box 155, Folder 12)
        - Hack, Nadine, 1986 (Box 155, Folder 13)
        - Hoy Pamela, undated (Box 155, Folder 14)
        - Johnston, Jill, 1977 (Box 156, Folder 1)
        - Kennedy, Florynce, undated (Box 156, Folder 2)
        - Levin, Tobe, 1977 (Box 156, Folder 3)
        - Levinson, Sandra, undated (Box 156, Folder 4)
        - Lidman, undated (Box 156, Folder 5)
        - Lurie, Diana, 1972-74 (Box 156, Folder 6)
        - McIntyre, Natalie, 1986 (Box 156, Folder 7)
        - McMurray, Nancy, 1978 (Box 156, Folder 8-9)
        - Means, Marianna, 1972 (Box 156, Folder 10)
        - Mills, Kay (re: Henry Hyde), 1977-78 (Box 156, Folder 11)
        - Morey-Gaines, Ann-Janine, 1977 (Box 156, Folder 12)
        - Morgan, Robin, 1977-79 (Box 156, Folder 13)
        - Morse, Sally, 1976 (Box 156, Folder 14)
        - Northcott, Kaye, 1977 (Box 156, Folder 15)
        - Northrup, Ann, undated (Box 156, Folder 16)
        - Pally, Marcia, 1983-84 (Box 156, Folder 17)
        - Phillips, Karen, 1972 (Box 156, Folder 18)
        - Pitchford, Kenneth, undated (Box 156, Folder 19)
        - Pollan, Rosalind, 1973 (Box 157, Folder 1)
        - Pratt, Hugh, undated (Box 157, Folder 2)
        - Quinn, Sally, undated (Box 157, Folder 3)
        - Raymond, Janice, undated (Box 157, Folder 4)
        - Rosser, Phyllis, 1973 (Box 157, Folder 5)
        - Russell, Michele, 1977 (Box 157, Folder 6)
        - Ruth, Sheila, 1977 (Box 157, Folder 7)
        - Scott, Ann Crittenden, 1973; undated (Box 157, Folder 8)
        - Serrin, Judith, 1972-74 (Box 157, Folder 9)
        - Shannon, Elaine, 1974 (Box 157, Folder 10)
        - Smith, Robert Ellis, 1973 (Box 157, Folder 11)
        - Tully, Mary Jean, undated (Box 157, Folder 12)
        - Tyerman, Denise de Garmo, undated (Box 157, Folder 13)
        - VanGelder, Rosalind, 1973 (Box 157, Folder 14)
        - Walker, Alice, 1973-83 (Box 157, Folder 15-16)
        - Warwick, Donald, 1974 (Box 158, Folder 1)
        - Wohl, Lisa, 1973-74; 1977; undated (Box 158, Folder 2-4)
        - Miscellaneous/ unidentified manuscripts (Box 158, Folder 5-6)
        - Miscellaneous/ unidentified manuscripts (Box 159, Folder 1-6)
      - Notes and miscellaneous, 1970-1981; undated (Box 159, Folder 7)
      - Notes and miscellaneous, 1970-1981; undated (Box 160, Folder 1-3)
      - Press clips and press releases, 1972-1986 (Box 160, Folder 4)
      - Production schedules and printer materials, 1977; 1986 (Box 160, Folder 5)
      - Tables of contents, article lists, outlines and covers, 1972-79 (Box 160, Folder 6)
      - Writers, 1973-74 (Box 160, Folder 7)
      - Writers' form letters, undated (Box 160, Folder 8)
    - Employees
      - Applications and stock information, 1977; 1987; undated (Box 160, Folder 9-10)
      - Insurance information, internal correspondence and memoranda, 1978-83; undated (Box 161, Folder 1-3)
    - Financial and legal: correspondence, forms, statements, analyses,memoranda, permissions, bills and receipts, 1972-88 (Box 161, Folder 4-20)
    - Fundraising
      - Contributions materials, 1976-81 (Box 161, Folder 21)
      - Correspondence, 1978-88 (Box 161, Folder 22)
      - Donors
        - Binello, Franca, 1984-85 (Box 162, Folder 1)
        - Dennis, Richard, 1985 (Box 162, Folder 2)
        - Ford Foundation, 1976-86 (Box 162, Folder 3)
        - Gund, Louise, 1986 (Box 162, Folder 4)
        - Steinem, Gloria, personal lists of potential donors, 1968-72; undated (Box 162, Folder 5)
      - Internal correspondence and memoranda, 1980; undated (Box 162, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous, 1985-91; undated (Box 162, Folder 7)
    - History, 1971-87 (Box 162, Folder 8)
    - Individuals
      - Brown, Rita Mae, 1974 (Box 162, Folder 9)
      - Carbine, Pat, 1974; 1979; 1984 (Box 162, Folder 10)
      - Chicago, Judy, 1979 (Box 162, Folder 11)
      - Harris, Elizabeth Forsling, 1971 (Box 162, Folder 12)
      - Hernandez, Aileen, undated (Box 162, Folder 13)
      - Hopewell, Richard, 1980-81 (Box 162, Folder 14)
      - Kennedy, Florynce, undated (Box 162, Folder 15)
      - Mikulski, Barbara, 1977 (Box 162, Folder 16)
      - Palevsky, Joan, 1983-84 (Box 162, Folder 17)
      - Pogrebin, Letty Cottin, 1984 (Box 162, Folder 18)
      - Pottinger, J. Stanley, 1975-80 (Box 162, Folder 19)
      - Salembier, Valerie, undated (Box 163, Folder 1)
      - Szuba, Joe, 1984 (Box 163, Folder 2)
      - Trudeau, Gary, 1984-86 (Box 163, Folder 3)
    - Interoffice memos and correspondence: Ms. Foundation office and Ms. magazine office, 1976-77 (Box 163, Folder 4)
    - Marketing
      - General, 1973; undated (Box 163, Folder 5)
      - Buttons, 1975-81; undated (Box 163, Folder 6)
      - Campus outreach, 1980; undated (Box 163, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, 1979-83 (Box 163, Folder 8)
      - Media estimates, 1979 (Box 163, Folder 9)
      - Press releases, 1980; undated (Box 163, Folder 10)
      - Promotion schedules, 1971-80 (Box 163, Folder 11)
      - Speaking engagements, 1983-84 (Box 163, Folder 12)
      - Tote bags, 1977-78 (Box 163, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971; 1979; undated (Box 163, Folder 14)
    - Research files, 1972-86 (Box 163, Folder 15-21)
    - Research files, 1972-86 (Box 164, Folder 1-13)
    - Research files, 1972-86 (Box 165, Folder 1-15)
    - Special projects
      - Alan Alda benefit, 1980 (Box 165, Folder 16)
      - Anniversaries, 1979; 1982; 1985; 1987 (Box 166, Folder 1-6)
      - Autobiographies and biographies for unidentified project, 1973 (Box 166, Folder 7-8)
      - Books
        - Anthology of Letters to the Editor, 1981 (Box 166, Folder 9)
        - Fine Lines: the Best of Ms. Fiction, undated (Box 166, Folder 10)
        - General, 1979-80 (Box 166, Folder 11)
      - Consulting, ABC, 1985-86 (Box 166, Folder 12)
      - Decade of Women exhibit, 1980 (Box 166, Folder 13)
      - The Dollmaker benefit, 1983-84 (Box 166, Folder 14)
      - H.R. 166, 1975 (Box 166, Folder 15)
      - Miscellaneous, 1980; 1985; undated (Box 166, Folder 16)
      - Ms. Enterprises, undated (Box 166, Folder 17)
      - Public TV series: proposal, 1973 (Box 166, Folder 18)
      - Radio projects, 1979 (Box 167, Folder 1)
      - Sisterhood is Global strategy meeting, 1984 (Box 167, Folder 2)
      - Studies, 1974 (Box 167, Folder 3)
      - Woman Alive, 1974-77 (Box 167, Folder 4)
      - Women Aloud, 1992 (Box 167, Folder 5)
      - Women of the Year: publicity, correspondence, and notes 1983-86 (includes autograph of Cyndi Lauper) (Box 167, Folder 6-9)
    - Subscriptions: correspondence, memoranda, and promotional materials, 1974-92 (Box 167, Folder 10-15)
  - National Women's Political Caucus
    - Affiliation: Steinem's notes on structure, 1971 (Box 168, Folder 1)
    - Bread and Roses Award, 1986 (Box 168, Folder 2)
    - By-laws, 1973 (Box 168, Folder 3)
    - Clippings 1971-73 (includes Dianne Feinstein) (Box 168, Folder 4)
    - Committees: agendas, minutes, memoranda, summaries (Box 168, Folder 5-16)
    - Conventions: travel receipts, printed material, correspondence, clippings (Box 168, Folder 17-21)
    - Coors boycott and League of Latin American Citizens: memoranda and printed material, 1977 (Box 168, Folder 22)